# **MARC MARQUEZ**

# **WEB DEVELOPER**

# **SUMMARY**

Detail driven Front End Developer with a passion for designing and delivering engaging and intuitive customer solutions. Possesses a unique knowledge base of refined industry experience, multi-platform cloud infrastructure expertise, extensive cross-functional team and timeline-oriented product delivery methodologies and proficiency in tech stack technologies such as JavaScript, HTML, jQuery, CSS and responsive web design.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## WEB DEVELOPER - The Agate Group, Penryn, CA / 2019

Serve as a key member of a professional services development team to build and deploy custom, high-quality, secure, and performant software solutions according to customer specification and deadlines while adhering to coding standards and best practices.

- Improved efficiency, readability, and maintainability of a Java web service using code refactoring, optimization, and unit testing.
- Debugged, diagnosed, and fixed multiple customer reported defects.
- Integrated 3<sup>rd</sup> party software using REST APIs.

# **LEAD ENGINEER -** Hewlett-Packard Enterprise, Roseville, CA / 2015 – 2017

Perform as the lead engineer to build and deploy a test framework (similar to Jenkins) CI/CD environment and create automated integration, system, regression, and acceptance test scripts for the release of embedded enterprise software.

- Reduced SDLC testing and deployment schedules by 70% by creating a reliable and scalable delivery pipeline that streamlined build integration, test execution, and deployment.
- Increased product release productivity by 300% by mentoring multiple engineers to use the test framework leading mgmt to initiate synchronous release cycles.

# SYSTEMS TEST ENGINEER / 2005 - 2015

Serve as a key member of a systems integration team to build cloud infrastructure test environments using various servers, networking and storage devices to test embedded enterprise software.

 Discovered, diagnosed and drove to resolution multiple bugs/defects by utilizing Root Cause Analysis (RCA) techniques to describe, monitor, and update issues by gathering support data such as OS, kernel, and trace logs, and validating fixes.

# **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AND TEST ENGINEER / 2001 - 2005**

Serve as a key member of a software team to develop a Java utility application for field engineers. Built scripts to automate UI testing of a Java enterprise management application. Created and executed test plans for network management software.

# **PROJECT WORK**

# **BUG/FEATURE TRACKER -** *Project / December 2018*

Web/mobile responsive Django application using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap for front-end and Python, MySQL for the back-end. Python code implements CRUD, account authentication, up-voting, REST and integrates with Stripe payments API to let users donate money.

### DATA DRIVEN VISUALIZATION - Project / August 2018

Web/mobile responsive Flask application presenting data in charts and histograms using HTML, CSS, DC.js, D3.js and Crossfilter.js on the UI and Python with MongoDB on the backend.

## **ROSEHIP PRODUCTIONS - Project / March 2018**

Web/mobile responsive Angular application promoting an events coordination company using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.

marc.marquez@gmail.com

(916) 715-0972

in linkedin.com/in/marc-marquez

marcmarquezdesigns.com

# **EDUCATION**

# BS / COMPUTER SCIENCE December 2000

CSU Sacramento Sacramento, CA

# DIPLOMA / FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT December 2018

CSU San Bernardino San Bernardino, CA

# **SKILLS**

### **LANGUAGES**

Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java, Apex, PHP

# **LIBRARIES**

jQuery, Crossfilter, DC, D3

## **FRAMEWORKS**

Django, Bootstrap, Salesforce, Spring, Angular, React, Flask, Laravel

### **DATABASES**

MySQL, MongoDB, SQL

# **PAYMENT PLATFORMS**

Stripe, PayPal

# **VERSION CONTROL**

Git, Github, BitBucket

# **OPERATING SYSTEMS**

Linux, Windows, Mac, VirtualBox

### OTHER TECHNICAL

Visual Studio, Heroku, Wireframing, Debugging, REST, WordPress, Jira

### **GRAPHICS**

Photoshop, Gimp

### **SOFT SKILLS**

Leadership, Collaboration, Communication, Problem Solving, Creativity, Documentation